CRISTINA DEL GAUDIO

Via di Pratale, 34 56127 Pisa (PI), Italy (+39) 327-259 4716
www.cristinadelgaudio.top
cristina.delgaudio@gmail.com

Analyst programmer (level IV) with 2+ years of professional experience in web development (frontend/backend), design, system management and maintenance. Experienced with all stages of development cycle for dynamic web projects. Very good background in project management and customer relations.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

LIBERSOFT SRL Navacchio, Pisa, Italy

Web Developer, Web Designer, System Manager, Full-Stack Developer

Sep 2013 – Present

- Design, build, or maintain web sites, using authoring or scripting languages, content creation tools, management tools, and digital media.
- Write, design, or edit web page content, or direct others producing content.
- Identify problems uncovered by testing or customer feedback, and correct problems or refer problems to appropriate personnel for correction.
- Maintain understanding of current web technologies or programming practices through continuing education, reading, or participation in professional conferences, workshops, or groups.
- Confer with management or development teams to prioritize needs, resolve conflicts, develop content criteria, or choose solutions.
- Communicate with network personnel or web site hosting agencies to address hardware or software issues affecting web sites.
- Install and configure hypertext transfer protocol (HTTP) servers and associated operating systems.
- Fixed bugs from existing websites and implemented enhancements that significantly improved web functionality and speed
- Renew domain name registrations.
- Perform or direct web site updates.
- Back up files from web sites to local directories for instant recovery in case of problems.
- Develop databases that support web applications and web sites.
- Establish appropriate server directory trees.
- Select programming languages, design tools, or applications.
- Register web sites with search engines to increase web site traffic.
- Provide clear, detailed descriptions of web site specifications such as product features, activities, software, communication protocols, programming languages, and operating systems software and hardware.
- Create web models or prototypes that include physical, interface, logical, or data models.
- Create designs, concepts, and sample layouts based on knowledge of layout principles and esthetic design concepts.
- Develop graphics and layouts for product illustrations, company logos, and Internet websites.
- Prepare illustrations or rough sketches of material, discussing them with clients or supervisors and making necessary changes.
- Use computer software to generate new images.
- Train over 10 staff members in internal web functions, including steps on how to independently make minor updates or changes.
- Recruit, hire, train and supervise staff, or participate in staffing decisions.

- Direct daily operations of department, analyzing workflow, establishing priorities, developing standards and setting deadlines.
- Assign and review the work of systems analysts, programmers, and other computer-related workers.
- Evaluate the organization's technology use and needs and recommend improvements, such as hardware and software upgrades.
- Purchase necessary equipment.

COMPUTER TECNICA ENGINEERING

Lucera, Foggia, Italy

Media Editor

Jan 2006 – Nov 2009

- Prepare, rewrite and edit copy to improve readability, or supervise others who do this work.
- Verify facts, dates, and statistics, using standard reference sources.
- Read copy or proof to detect and correct errors in spelling, punctuation, and syntax.
- Plan the contents of publications according to the publication's style, editorial policy, and publishing requirements.
- Read, evaluate and edit manuscripts or other materials submitted for publication and confer with authors regarding changes in content, style or organization, or publication.
- Allocate print space for story text, photos, and illustrations according to space parameters and copy significance, using knowledge of layout principles.
- Search standard reference materials, including online sources and the Internet, to answer patrons' reference questions.

VOLUNTEERING EXPERIENCE

L'ALBA ASSOCIAZIONE

Pisa, PI, Italy

Web Developer, System Manager, Graphic Designer

Nov 2009 – Nov 2010

- Design, build, or maintain web sites, using authoring or scripting languages, content creation tools, management tools, and digital media.
- Determine sources of web page or server problems, and take action to correct such problems.
- Review or update web page content or links in a timely manner, using appropriate tools.
- Write, design, or edit web page content, or direct others producing content.
- Administer internet/intranet infrastructure, including components such as web, file transfer protocol (FTP), news and mail servers.
- Analyze user needs to determine technical requirements.
- Determine size and arrangement of illustrative material and copy, and select style and size of type.
- Develop graphics and layouts for product illustrations, company logos, and Internet websites.
- Develop briefings, brochures, multimedia presentations, web pages, promotional products, technical illustrations, and computer artwork for use in products, technical manuals, literature, newsletters and slide shows.
- Evaluate code to ensure that it is valid, is properly structured, meets industry standards and is compatible with browsers, devices, or operating systems.
- Create basic designs, drawings, and illustrations for events.
- Mark up, paste, and assemble final layouts to prepare layouts for printer.
- Use computer software to generate new images.
- Plan, develop, and provide training and staff development programs, using knowledge of the effectiveness of methods such as classroom training, demonstrations, on-the-job training, meetings, conferences, and workshops.

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITA' DI PISA

Computer Science, Sep 2006 - Present

Main Subjects:

- Java/C/SQL/PHP programming
- Algorithms
- Discrete mathematics and numerical analysis
- Databases
- Cryptography
- Computer Architecture
- Computer Networks and protocols
- Software engineering
- Concurrent programming
- System programming
- Digital Audio

LICEO SCIENTIFICO R. BONGHI

Lucera, FG, Italy

High School Diploma, Jul 2006

ADDITIONAL SKILLS

- Spoken Languages: **Italian (native)**, **English** (proficient), **Spanish** (conversant), French (basic knowledge)
- Known programming languages: **HTML**, XML, **CSS**, **JavaScript**, **JQuery**, **Python**, Java, C, **PHP**, YAML, TOML, SQL, Bash
- Proficient in Operating Systems: Linux (Ubuntu, Mint, Debian, KDE), Windows (2000, XP, Vista, 7, 8)
- Proficient in **Drupal**, **WordPress**, Moodle, SugarCRM, SuiteCRM (frontend/backend development)
- Proficient in **Django**, **Symfony**, **Hugo**, **AngularJS** web app development frameworks
- Proficient in MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB databases, Apache and Nginx web servers
- Proficient in Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator, GIMP, InkScape, Krita
- Proficient in **Bootstrap** and Materialize frameworks
- Use of **Git** for software versioning

Pisa, PI, Italy